A Guide to the University of Virginia Summer School Records, 1909-1959
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
University of Virginia Summer School Records 1909-1959
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-13/1/3.601
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was an archival transfer from the Summer Session Office, ca. 1960.
Scope and Content
The collection contains administrative correspondence concerning various courses and programs; general topical files including a small one on African American applicants and others that document life at the University during World War II as well as various files of a routine administrative nature; reports; form letters; faculty appointments; scholarship applications; personnel files; requests for applications; statistics; budget and cost-income analyses; degree applicants; scholarship applications; clippings; correspondence of Extension Dean George B. Zehmer and miscellaneous correspondence of other deans.
Contents List
- Course Materials- Administrative Correspondence, Suggestions ca. 1940-1959
  - Art, Architecture, Biology (Mt. Lake), Chemistry, and Commercial Education (Box 1)
  - Commercial Education, Economics, Education, Engineering (Box 2)
  - English, Foreign Affairs, Modern Languages, Geography (Box 3)
  - German, History, Library Science, Math, Music, Nursing Education, Philosophy, Physical Education, Physics (Box 4)
  - Physics, Political Science, Psychology, Public Speaking, Reading Clinic, Religion, Secretarial Courses, Rural Social Economics, Sociology, Speech Correction, Speech & Drama (Box 5)
  - Speech & Drama, Dramatic Art, Education Workshop (Box 6)
- Alphabetical Files- General Boxes
  - Acceptances Witholding Tax Forms, Administrative Board, Administrative Committee, Adult Education, Advertising, Alderman Library, American County Life Ass., Announcements, Annual Report 1948, Applications for Positions (Box 7)
  - Boaz, Miss Brydon, Building and Grounds, Bulletins other Colleges, Bursar, CCC Director's Conference, Cabell Hall Exhibit Space, Calendar (Box 8)
  - Caps and Gowns (Cotrell & Leonard), Catalogue, Certification of Other States, Changes, Charlottesville Chamber of Commerce, Children's Art Classes, Classrooms, Class Schedules (Box 9)
  - Colored Applicants, Minutes of Executive Committee, Committee on Higher Education, Comm. Nat. Ed. Ass., Summer Quarter Committee, Commons, Conference, Banker's Conference (Box 10)
  - Convocation, Co-operative Education Assistance, Counselorship Applications-Appointments, Dance Reciepts, Darden, Direction of Masters Theses, Doctor's Certificates, Eight weeks Session, Special Examination, Re-exams, Extensions (Box 11)
  - Faculty, Faculty housing, Prospects, Federal Aid, Final exercise, Fletcher, Richard R., Fraternity Houses (Box 12)
  - Fraternity Houses Occupied, Golf course, Grades, Graduate Studies (Box 13)
  - Graduation Exercises, Dr. Hall, Dr. Hammond, Honor Committee, Hostess, Housing (Box 14)
  - Housing, Institute on Public Housing, Institute of Professional Relations, International Student Club, Law, Leaves of Absence, Lectures, Library, Library Acquisitions, Library Committee, Loans, Madison Hall Hostess, Dr. Manahan's Letters, Marine Corps, Dean of Medicine (Box 15)
  - Maphis, Meetings- Engagements, Methodist Church 1940, Military Service, Mimeograph Correspondence, etc. (I. P. Dick Co.), Minister, Ministers & Choir Directors, Miscellaneous (Box 16)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 17)
  - Miscellaneous, National Science Foundation, Newspaper clippings, Night Watchmen, Notes, Orders (Box 18)
  - Parent-Teachers, Payroll & Approval Data '48, Permits-Cars '43, Petition for S. S. Committee, Pledges (Teachers), Positions Wanted, Post Office, Practice Teaching, Printers Copy, Copy of Printing Material 1943, Professional Relations, Radio, Receipts '39, Recommendations (Box 19)
  - Reduced Railroads, References, Personal Refunds of 1943, Registrar, Registration, Conduct and Regulations, Requests from Other schools and Businesses, Room Assignments, 1944 (Box 20)
  - Schedule, 1943, Schedule Changes 1944, Schedule for Ringing Bells, Scholarships, Seminars for Naval Officers 1942, Frank M. Sibley, Jr., Edward R. Slaughter, Lindsay J. Stiler, Student Council, Student Health, Suggestions (Box 21)
  - Summer Quarter (S. Q.), Miscellaneous 1945, S. Q. Room Fees, S. Q. Second Term 1943, Letters Superintendents Questionaires, S. Q. Texts 1945, S. Q. 1945, S. Q. General 1943-1944, S. Q. Pending, S. Q. State Organizations, Summer School Docket, Summer Session Enrollment Data, Summer Session (correspondence with students), Summer Session, Virginia Deans and Directors, Supplies and Equipment, Suspension, Tabulating Division, Tax Exemption (Box 22)
  - Teaching Training, Telegrams, Traditional Forms of Social Recreation, Traffic Control, Vesper Service, Veterans, Veterans Administration, Virginia State Chamber of Commerce, 1929 (Box 23)
  - Virginia Academy of Science, Virginia Resources of Southern Assitance of Science and Industry 1944, WCHV, Washington Celebration, Withdrawls, Workshops, Workshop of Community Development, Workshop, Meeting on, Workshop of School and Community Relations '43 (Box 24)
- Summer Session Report of the Ass. of Deans and Directors
  - Summer Session Reports of the Ass. of Deans and Directors, 1925-1934 (Box 25)
  - Summer Session Reports of the Ass. of Deans and Directors, 1935-1947 (Box 26)
  - Summer Session Reports of the Ass. of Deans and Directors, 1948-1952 (Box 27)
  - Summer Session Reports of the Ass. of Deans and Directors, 1952-1959 (Box 28)
- Summer School Reports
  Boxes 29-32
  - Summer School Reports, 1909-1927 (Box 29)
  - Summer School Reports, 1924-1931 (Box 30)
  - Summer Reports, 1931-1943 (Box 31)
  - Summer School Reports, 1944-1959 (Box 32)
- Form Letters, 1924-1958
  Boxes 33-37.
  - Form Letters, 1924-1930 (Box 33)
  - Form Letters, 1925-1939 (Box 34)
  - Form Letters, 1934-1943 (Box 35)
  - Form Letters, 1948-1956 (Box 36)
  - Form Letters, 1957-1958 (Box 37)
- Faculty Appointments, 1951-1958 (Box 38-39)
  Loose form letters of appointment.
- Education Courses and Applications for Scholarships, 1942-1959 (Box 40-41)
- Personnel Boxes, 1939-1960 (Box 42-43)
- Requests for Applications, Applications, Handbooks
- Statistics Boxes, 1922-1959
  Boxes 44-45.
  - Statistics Box, 1922-1944 (Box 44)
  - Statistic Box, 1944-1959 (Box 45)
- Budget and Cost-Income Analysis, 1927-1959
  Boxes 46-47.
  - Budget and Cost-Income Analysis, 1927-1951 (Box 46)
  - Budget and Cost-Income Analysis, 1951-1959 (Box 47)
  - Entertainment- concerts, films, programs, advertisint correspondence, 1934-1957 (Box 48)
  - Radio- University Programs; Others, Manuals, 1937-1942 (Box 49)
  - Degree Applicants- List, Correspondence with, Excuses from Exercise, 1943-1959 (Box 50)
  - Scholarship Applications, annnouncements, administrative correspondence (Box 51)
  - College topics (1951,1956); Degree Applicants: Lists, Excuses from exercises, correspondence, 1947-1955 (Box 52)
  - Newspaper clippings (Daily Progress, College Topics: 1951-1958), College Topics correspondence (Box 53)
  - Zehmer Correspondence, 1938-1951 (Box 54)
  - Zehmer Correspondence, 1938-1951 (Box 55)
  - Eason correspondence- St. Department of Education, 1924-1939 (Box 56)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1923-1959
    Marion H. Hamilton, Secretary 1946. Dean R. W. Cherry, 1956; J. B. Chase, 1954-1956; Parker C. Griffin, Assistant Dean, 1956-1957; Registrar, 1956-1959; Ruth Richer, Registrar, 1933-1947; Dean Lewis Hammond, 1947-1950; Dean R. J. Costen, 1927-1941; Dean Charles G. Maphis, 1923-1935.